Guide to the Stanford University, Department of History, Honors Theses
Stanford University. Libraries.
- Theses, 1997; Accession ARCH-1997-136
  - Hardwick, Heather, Britain, The Commonwealth, and Europe: Decolonization in Africa and the Decision to Join the European Economic Community 1957-1963., June 1997 (Box 1)
  - Honey, James, Policy and Politics in the Papagueria: A Twentieth Century, Cross-Border HIstory of the Tohono O'odham., May 30, 1997 (Box 1)
  - Mackh, Megan, Visions of Destiny, Designs on Dominance: Divining the perceptions of teh Nineteenth-Century American Elite., May 19, 1997 (Box 1)
  - Marsh, Anthony, From Pledge to Principle: Religions Non-Interference Udner British Indirect Rule in Northern Nigeria (1900-1912)., May 1997 (Box 1)
  - Martin, Abigail Taylor, Constructing the Activist Housewife: The Dilemmas of Liminality and Coalition For Older Female Protesters of the Vietnam War., May 16, 1997 (Box 1)
  - Miyashiro, James, Education's Role in Maintaining and Challenging the Racial Oligarchy in Twentieth-Century Hawaii., May 1997 (Box 2)
  - Musick, Michael, The Creation of the Maasai REserves 1900-1954., May 1997 (Box 2)
  - Paz, Andrea Margot, Behind Barbed Wire: The Internment of Allied Civilians by the Japanese in Shanghai., May 1997 (Box 2)
  - Post, Alison E., The Great Society and its Discontents: The Story and Impact of "Community Action" in East Palo Alto, CA., 1997 (Box 2)
  - Richardson, Caleb, The Internment Camp as Public School: P. G. Wodehouse and World War II., May 16, 1997 (Box 2)
  - Shabat, Matthew, Clarity Through Purpose: Understanding the Vietnam Decisions of John F. Kennedy, September - November 1963., May 16, 1997 (Box 2)
  - Soloman, Debra T., Jay Lovestone and the AFL-CIO Face Italian Communism., May 20, 1997 (Box 2)
  - St. John, Rachel, The Enterprise Reservoir: A Mormon Response to an Arid Environment., May 15, 1997 (Box 2)
  - Wack, Kevin, Liverpool and the Heysel Riot: A Local Historical Approach to Soccer Hooliganism., May 16, 1997 (Box 2)
  - Yang, Roger, Conflict and Scarcity During the California Drought, 1987-1993., May 30, 1997 (Box 2)
- Theses, 1998; Accession ARCH-1998-279
  - Angelica, James, Inquisitors and Society: The Relationship between the Bishop of Pamiers and Local Peoples, 1318-1325., 1998 (Box 1)
  - Balakrishnan, Prithika, Perez v. Lippold - The Historical Origins of "Color Blindness" in Anti-Miscegenation Law., May 15, 1998 (Box 1)
  - Bell, Mark R., Apocalypse How? Baptists during the English Revolution., May 1998 (Box 1)
  - Cain, Kwame Nkrumah, Post-Colonial Zimbabwe: Struggles After the Struggle., May 29, 1998 (Box 1)
  - Choi, Steven, The Case of Bruce Franklin., May 15, 1998 (Box 1)
  - Ellickson, Jenny, "Playing with the Faith of Fifty Million People": The Impact of the 1919 World Series on a Nation of Fans., May 15, 1998 (Box 1)
  - Fastov, Alexandra, 1980s National Fantasy Machine and 1990s Hole in the Ground: The Birth and Premature Death of the Superconducting Super Collider, 1983-1993, 1998; 1 folder(s)
  - Fox, Jennifer, From Paris to Union Square: The Development of the San Francisco French Community., May 22, 1998 (Box 1)
  - Hsiao, Grace C., More Than Women's Work: China Inland Misson's Nellie Marchbank., May 1998 (Box 2)
  - Jackson, Katrinka, The Linguistic Impact of Colonialism on Education in Kenya., 1998 (Box 2)
  - Johnson, Soren, An Oxford Mercer's Life., May 18, 1998 (Box 2)
  - Levin, Daniel B., The Road Not Taken: Bretton Woods and its Opponents., May 1998 (Box 2)
  - Logan, Timothy J., Prophet of the Fall: Andrei Amalrik and the Collapse of the Soviet Union., 1998 (Box 2)
  - Polu, Sandhya, Struggles for Authority and the Right to Practice Medicine: Disputes within the Medical Profession in Early Modern London.., May 15, 1998 (Box 2)
  - Robinson, Emily, Their Lives for a Union: The Ford Hunger March and its Impact on the Development of the UAW., 1998 (Box 2)
  - Salmon, Shawn Connelly, Destalinization and the Historian's Word: the Case of Aleksandr Nekrich., May 15, 1998 (Box 2)
  - Schatzberg, Melissa, The Columbia Salmon: A Casualty in the Race to Prosper from a River., May 15, 1998 (Box 3)
  - Strom, Ryan E., Un pueblo quemado. The Rise and Fall of the Protestant Church Among the Chamula Indians of Chiapas., 1998 (Box 3)
  - Wood, Julia Erin, Growing Alienation and Rising Consciousness: Northern White Women's Shifting Conceptions of their Position within the Southern Civil Rights Struggle, 1965., May 15, 1998 (Box 3)
- Theses, 1999; Accession ARCH-2000-026
  - Addo, Shika Abui, Kwame Nkrumah of Chana: Nationalism in British West Africa., 1999 (Box 1)
  - Agee, Gretchen, Giving Them Homes in the West: The New York Children's Aid Society and the Reception of its Children in Minnesota, 1881-1883., 1999 (Box 1)
  - Aguirre, Tobias Raphael, Love in Action: Engaged Buddhism in Vietnam., 1999 (Box 1)
  - Boswell, Nathaniel, The Sound of Silence: The American Worker Film Movement 1900-1920., 1999 (Box 1)
  - Brown, Deborah Anna, Journeys in History: The Holocaust Memory and Identity in israel, the United States and German., 1999 (Box 1)
  - Buckley, Michael, With Hearts Grown Brutal: the Indoctrination and Disillusionment of the Young Irish Republican Army., 1999 (Box 1)
  - Cameron, Sarah, America through Italian Eyes: the Occupation of Naples., 1999 (Box 1)
  - Chapman, Erin D., Real Blackness: the Gendered Identities of Black Power and Black Feminism., 1999 (Box 1)
  - Dudlo, Jim, "One Thing to Rule them All:" The Santa Fe Ring and the Origins of the Lincoln County War., 1999 (Box 1)
  - Erdstein, Max J., London Transported: Art, Industry, and Modernism. (Box 1)
  - Goldman, Jeff, Voting for Death: How Capital Punishment became a Political Issue in America 1950-1988. (Box 2)
  - Hangai, Dana, Forbidden Soil: The Japanese and the fight against California''s Alien Land Law. (Box 2)
  - Hildner, Laura, Radical transformations: Stanford's Participation in the Mississippi Voter Registration Drives of 1963-1965 and the Rise of Campus Activism., 1999 (Box 2)
  - Knapp, Elisabeth C. R., Claiming the Right to be Let Alone: The Early Develpment of the Right to Privacy in American Law, 1890-1928., 1999 (Box 2)
  - Kovac, Amy Lynn, Historical "Glasnost" and Its Impact on Teaching History in Soviet Secondary Schools., 1999 (Box 2)
  - Leff, Marni Rosene, Gender and the Holocaust: Concentration Camp brothels in Nazi Germany., 1999 (Box 2)
  - Leslau, Noam, Conflict of Nations, A Discourse Analysis. "Limpieza de Sangre", Medieval Communities and the Emergence of the Spanish National Identity., 1999 (Box 2)
  - Lindsay, Camilla, "Women Needed Now": Boeing Aircraft and The Second World War., 1999 (Box 2)
  - Lipkowitz, Elise, Pacific Perspectives: David Starr Jordan, Payson Treat, Yamato Ichihashi and the Emerging American Discourse on Japan, 1905-1945., 1999 (Box 2)
  - Logan, Elizabeth Ann, Neil Jordan's Exploration of Violence in "Michael Collins": The Gun, The Lens, and the Future., 1999 (Box 2)
  - MacKinnon, Alison Anne, History and Myth: Three Stories of the London Blitz., 1999 (Box 3)
  - McCulloch, George, A Broader Unionism: The Justice for Janitors Campaign in Silicon Valley., 1999 (Box 3)
  - McKinnell, James, The First Ugandan Sleeping sickness Epidemic, 1900-1925., 1999 (Box 3)
  - Morehead, William, Home "Congruent" Home: Cohousing within the HIstorical Context of the American Residential Environment., 1999 (Box 3)
  - Moroney, Robin, Boax! Boax! Boax! Samuel Johnson's Dictionary and the STate of the British Language 1700-1800., 1999 (Box 3)
  - Quinones, Catherine, "The Right Stuff": The Portrayal of the Early American Space Program and its Heroes on Film., 1999 (Box 3)
  - Robbins, Rebecca, Interpreting Jewishness Past and Present: Representation and Display in the New York Jewish Museum and the Jewish Museum of San Francisco., 1999 (Box 3)
  - Roth, Deborah, Ferdinand Hodler's "The Departure of the Jena Students in 1813"; Intersections of Traditional and Modern Art., 1999 (Box 3)
  - Wang, Sam C., Bloody Legacy: Japanese Wartime Brutality and the Rape of Nanking., 1999 (Box 3)
  - Yoda, Steven, A Portrait of the Life of James M. Omura, American Champion of Civil Rights., 1999 (Box 3)
- Theses, 2000; Accession ARCH-2001-013
  - Baker, Kimberley, They Answered the Call of the Nation, but Who Heard Their Cry?: Racial Discrimination against African-American Women in the Women's Army Auxiliary Corps and the Women's Army Corps During World War II., May 2000 (Box 1)
  - Bullard, Ward, Bridging the Odds: the Untold Story of the Financial and Legal Obstacles to the Golden Gate Bridge., May 2000 (Box 1)
  - Chen, Allan, Die Atombombe: the Struggle to Understand the German Atomic Bomb Project., May 2000 (Box 1)
  - Clements, Nicholas Paul, Will Morning Once More Greet Us? - Family Life in England during the Evacuation and the Blitz as seen through the eyes of Mass Observation., May 2000 (Box 1)
  - Collett, Nathan, Thaaism and the Renewal of Traditional Culture and Religion in Kenya, 1900s-1990s; "Thaaism: Community of Resistance," video, copyright 1999-200, also included., May 2000 (Box 1)
  - Dodson, Carrie, Speaking a New Past: Oral History in South Africa., May 2000 (Box 1)
  - Eyal, Yonatan, Nullification-Era Unionism in South Carolina, 1828-1834., May 2000 (Box 1)
  - Gillespie, Nathan Erik, In America's Backyard: the Granadian Revolution and the United States, 1979-1983., May 2000 (Box 1)
  - Keefer, Bryan, From Prunes and Apricots to Art and Wine: Festivals, Society and Environment in Mountain View, California, 1915-1999., May 2000 (Box 2)
  - Kulkarni, Rajan, The Second Revolution: Transforming Biology into an Information Science., May 2000 (Box 2)
  - Long, Duncan, Proxy Imperialism and the Drive for Profit: The British South Africa Company in Matabeleland and Mashonaland, 1889-1897., May 2000 (Box 2)
  - Lozano, Rosina, The Struggle for Inclusion: A Study of the Community Service Organization in East Los Angeles, 1947-1951., May 2000 (Box 2)
  - Moffic, Evan, The Making of an American Zionist: Reevaluating Louis Brandeis., May 2000 (Box 2)
  - Nordby, Evan, Fire and Sandstone: Anti-Vietnam War Activism at Stanford, 1966-1970., June 2000 (Box 2)
  - Saporito, Anna, Reasoning With Her: the Place of Margaret Cavendish and Anne Conway in the Scientific Revolution., May 2000 (Box 2)
  - Thompkins, Megan, To "Wait for No Man": The Modern Woman's Conundrum in Early Post-World War I Britain., May, 2000 (Box 3)
  - Thompson, Sarah, Maids and Madams, Mistresses and 'Boys': Locating the White Settler Woman in Southern Rhodesia, 1890-1930s., May 2000 (Box 3)
  - Tompkins, Megan, To "Wait for No Man": The Modern Woman's Conundrum in Early Post-World War I Britain., May 2000 (Box 3)
  - Webel, Mari K., "Misrepresenting Egypt": Cultural Identity and Political Dissent in Southern Illinois during the Lecompton Crisis of 1858., May 2000 (Box 3)
- Theses, 2001; Accession ARCH-2001-166
  - Agee, Megan, There's No Such Thing as a Free Lunch: The Origins of the National School Lunch Program., May 2001 (Box 1)
  - Auld, Sara, Women and Medicine in the West: Charlotte Blake Brown and the Founding of the San Francisco Children's Hospital, 1875-1904., May 2001 (Box 1)
  - Baribault, Maryann, The American Boycott of the Moscow Olympics: A Study of the Relationship between Politics and Athletics., May 2001 (Box 1)
  - Brubaker, Jared, Different Perspectives on a Shared Identity: The Moriscos of Deza, 1570-1611., May 2001 (Box 1)
  - Carter, Brian Jonas, Doctors of Resistance: A Study of Nineteenth Century Slave Medical Practitioners in the U. S. South., May 2001 (Box 1)
  - Cho, Seung-Min Samuel, The Kwangju Tragedy: An Entanglement of Regionalism and People's Desire for Democracy in the Korean Peninsula., May 2001 (Box 1)
  - DeBakcsy, Dale, Beyond Wagner: The Triumph of Musical Diversity over Nazi Ideology in the Third Reich., May 2001 (Box 1)
  - Goss, Rasanah, Raised to be Slaves: The Childhood Experience During Colonial American Slavery., June 2001 (Box 1)
  - Lau, Olivia Cie, An Explosive Issue in an Era of Social Change: The Evolving Discussion over the Use of he Atomic Bomb in the 1960s., May 2001 (Box 2)
  - Marshak, Adam Kolman, The Many Faces of King Herod: Client Kingship and Hellenist Jewish Monarchy in the Herodian Dynasty., May 2001 (Box 2)
  - Meyer, Sarah, The Spirit of Enterprise: The Terra Nova Expedition and Captain Scott's Heroic Failure., May 2001 (Box 2)
  - Montz, Zachary, The Logic of Escalation: Vietnam Decision-Making in the Johnson Administration., May 2001 (Box 2)
  - Mulhauser, Dana, Women at Work: Gender and Class Consciousness in the New York Women's Labor Movement, 1900-1914., May 2001 (Box 2)
  - Presser, Elisabeth Catherine, Creation of Authority: John Stuart Mill and the American Civil War., May 2001 (Box 2)
  - Rauh, Grace, The May 1968 Student Uprising in Senegal: A Sruggle for Independence., May 2001 (Box 3)
  - Sayn-Wittgenstein, Anna zu, Teaching the History of the Third Reich: Its Affect on German Youth today as Measured and Analyzed 1999-2001., May 2001 (Box 3)
  - Schmidt, Erin, Daughters of Vera: Womanhood in the Early Soviet Era., May 2001 (Box 3)
  - Schwegman, Jeffrey L., The Revolt of Eden: The Transformation of Nature in the Novels of Emile Zola., May 2001 (Box 3)
  - Shamsid-Deen, Masud Shakir, Martin Luther King, Jr. and his Relationship to Africa, 1956-1967., May 2001 (Box 3)
  - Toth, Michael, The Coming of a Capitalist: Religion, Politics, Radicalism and Michael Novak., May 2001 (Box 3)
- Theses, 2002; Accession ARCH-2002-183
  - Ahmed, Shad, The USAID, Egypt, & the Deveolpment Industrial Bank: A Constrained Experience., Spring 2002 (Box 1)
  - Baker, Grey Donaldson, The Rapido River Battles: The 36th "Texas" Infantry Division in War and Peace., May 24, 2002 (Box 1)
  - Berson, Jennifer, Prague Spring, the Communist Part, and Population Policy: The Tradeoff Between Abortion and Birth Rates in Czechoslovakia., May 2002 (Box 1)
  - Chen, Ada, For the Greatest Benefit of the Greatest Number: The Evolution of Benefit-Cost Analysis Through the Development of the Central Valley Project., May 2002 (Box 1)
  - Coates, Benjamin, Understanding Inaccuracy: The U.S. Embassy and Human Rights Reporting in El Salvador, 1979-1984., May 10, 2002 (Box 1)
  - Crisham, Mary, Molding Mary: Power of the Symbol of Mary in the Creation., May 28, 2002 (Box 1)
  - Dahlke, Courtney, Three Kings: Genre and Authorship in Early Medieval Irish Kingship Texts., May 2002 (Box 1)
  - Dunlop, Catherine, Redefining Resistance: Maquis of Ain and Their Parade at Oyonnax, 1943., May 2002 (Box 1)
  - Hawley, Joshua, Preacher of Righteousness; The Social and Political Thought of Theodore Roosevelt., May 2002 (Box 1)
  - Hogberg, Sverker, Uppsala University in the Early Modern Period: Reflections of State, Society and Religion., May 2002 (Box 2)
  - Hsu, Helen, The Power of Culture in the American Censorship of Ulysses., Spring 2002 (Box 2)
  - Lambert, Melissa, Fascism, Communism, and Collective Bargaining: The Salinas Lettuce Strike of 1936., May 2002 (Box 2)
  - Lilien, Benjamin, Striking a Response to the Depression: The Story of the Amalgamated in Baltimore., May 24, 2002 (Box 2)
  - Lopez, Elizabeth, Two Women's Worlds: Jane Addams' Relationship with the Immigrant Mothers of Hull House., May 24, 2002 (Box 2)
  - Martin, Bry, From Comprehension to Conscience: Reason, Fallibility and the Collapse of Church Authority in the Writings of Bishop Benjamin Hoadly, 1676-1717., May 24, 2002 (Box 2)
  - McKiernan, Caitrin, Young Women in the Age of Transformation: Three Case Studies from Contemporary China., May 2002 (Box 2)
  - Ng, Charlene, American Society and Cancer: Skin Cancer from 1978-2001., May 24, 2002 (Box 2)
  - Olson, Alexander, Our Leschi: A Story of Puget Sound History., 2002 (Box 3)
  - Poon, Lydia, In the Service of the World: Stanford University and the Progressive Ideal in Wartime, 1916-1918., May 10, 2002 (Box 3)
  - Port, Elissa, E.C. Bridgman, S. Wells Williams and Peter Parker: The Missionary Contribution to Sino-American Policy., May 10, 2002 (Box 3)
  - Port, Jeffrey, A Quarter Secion of Water: The Fight Against Agri Business and the Westlands Water District, 1958-1982., June 2002 (Box 3)
  - Ratner, Ariel, Explaining Failure: The Crisis of Argentine Neoliberalism from 1989-2001., Spring 2002 (Box 3)
  - Reddy, Anitha, Property and Politics: Legal Reflections of the Transition from Republic to Democracy, 1972-1805., May 24, 2002 (Box 3)
  - Renlund, Ashley, J. Robert Oppenheimer: Interpreting the Responsibility of Scientists., June 2002 (Box 3)
  - Scarlet-Trotter, Rachel, From Sunbonnets to Bloomers: A Changing Frontier for Women in Victorian America., May 2002 (Box 3)
  - Schaefer, Daniel, American Judaism Reconsidered: Religion and Nationalsim in the Thought of Irving Reichert., 2002 (Box 3)
  - Smith, Stephen Gabriel, Rendezvous with Reform: The Politics of Raymond Moley and the Brains Trust, 1932-1936., 2002 (Box 3)
  - Turner, Laura, Tell the American People They are Murdering Us: American Reactions to the South African War and the Transition in U.S. Foreign Policy, 1889-1902., May 10, 2002 (Box 4)
  - Vinson, Amanda, A Twice Told Tale: Kate Cummings and the Cult of the Lost Cause., May 2002 (Box 4)
  - Whitgob, Emily, Objects of Empire: The Rise and Fall of the Metis in French West Africa., Spring 2002 (Box 4)
  - Wilgus, Taryn, Carrying the Movement: The Role of Women in SNCC., May 10, 2002 (Box 4)
  - Williams, Angela, An American Tradition: Celebrating Independence Day with Whites and New Perce Indians., June 2002 (Box 4)
- Theses, 2003; Accession ARCH-2003-180
  - Aikman, Amanda, Representations of Sexuality in American Women's Magaines, 1951-1986., May 16, 2003 (Box 1)
  - Amador, Daniel, "Innercity Griots": How Rap Artists Have Reconstructed the Civil Rights Era., June 2003 (Box 1)
  - Banerjee, Shouvik, The Constrained Enlightenment: Thomas Jefferson, Organized Religion, and Visions of a Virtuous Society., 2003 (Box 1)
  - Berland, Katharine josephine, Gray Propaganda, White Noise, and Black Lists: Radio Free Europe and the Dissident Movement in Czechoslovakia in 1968, 1977 and 1989., May 2003 (Box 1)
  - Kamhi, Alison Elizabeth, Thirteen Years Later: The Memory of a Nation and the Consequences of Reunification for East German Identity: A Case Study of the Reactions and Perceptions of Rostock Citizens to German Reunification., May 2003 (Box 1)
  - Khamky, Jolynn, Liberalization to Divestment: Egypt 1960-2000., 2003 (Box 1)
  - Kitchell, Sarah, Khrushchev, Corn, and Coexistence: U.S.-U.S.S.R. Rapprochement through Agricultural Exchange., May 2003 (Box 2)
  - Lee, Anthony J., Debunking the Jackie Robinson Myth: The Complete Story of How Baseball Became Fully Integrated., May 15, 2003 (Box 2)
  - Mishook, David Reis, "All They Can Be for England": The Enlistment Question and Russian Jews in Britain during the First World War., May 2003 (Box 2)
  - Ragep, Anwar, Citizenship and Its Discontents: The End of Britain's Mediterranean Empire., May 23, 2003 (Box 2)
  - Sale, Anna, Campaigning to Save the Triangle District: Urban policy, Race, and Resistance Organizing in Charleston, West Virginia, 1965-1972., June 2003 (Box 2)
  - Shapiro, Rachel, The Jefferson Image in the Lincoln Mind: The Influence of Thomas Jefferson on Abraham Lincoln's Political Thought., May 16, 2003 (Box 2)
  - St. Clair, Eva, Medieval Western Psychology: The Influence of Algazel., 2003 (Box 2)
  - Stevens, Lily, "The Message of the Dome": The United States Capitol in the Popular Media, 1865-1946., May 2003 (Box 3)
  - Sutton, Trevor, A Life in Print: Knowledge, Books and Power in the World of Gabriel Naude, 1600-1653., May 16, 2003 (Box 3)
  - Sydow, Nicholas Mark, A Study: Imperialism: A History of J.A. Hobson's Imperialism: A Study and its Influences in Hobson's Writing, 1898-1902., May 2003 (Box 3)
  - Thurston, Robin, Troubled Neighborhoods: The Social Effects of the Northern Ireland Conflict in North and West Belfast, 1974-1994., May 16, 2003 (Box 3)
  - Weissbourd, Ben, Dams, Wild Trout, and Whirling Disease: Creating a Fishery on Montan's Madison River., June 2003 (Box 3)
  - Zeratsky, Elizabeth, Wife, Mother, Dissident: The Complex Roles of Women in the Soviet Human Rights Movement., May 2003 (Box 3)
- Theses, 2004; Accession ARCH 2004-227
  - Cassel, Amanda, We Refuse To Serve: The Resistance, The Draft, and The Sixties Generation., May 2004 (Box 1)
  - Dawson, Emily Kate, The Jewish Mother Reconsidered: A Portrait of Jewish Motherhood On The West Coast of the U.S. 1949-1960., May 2004 (Box 1)
  - Evans, Erinn, "Not a Person of Importance": Bruna Talluri, Rebel, Writer, Intellectual., May 14, 2004 (Box 1)
  - Giannella, Eric, Unterstanding Histories of Innovation Through Quantitative Patent Data., May 14, 2004 (Box 1)
  - Gilbert, Claire, Reading Cultures: the textual Transmission between Musilm and Christian Communities in al-Andalus., May 14, 2004 (Box 1)
  - Gin, Kathryn, "Dead Christians" and "Heathen Converts": Home and Foreign Missionary Efforts with the White and Chinese Populations in California, 1850-1870., May 14, 2004 (Box 1)
  - Grosslight, Justin, Galileo Reinvented: Patronage and Publication Following Galileo's Condemnation., May 14, 2004 (Box 1)
  - Hudson, William E., Rediscovering Europe: Jacques Maritain and the Wartime Challenge to Democracy, Peace and Community, 1935-1946., May 14, 2004 (Box 1)
  - Hurlbutt, Therese E., Why Would Anyone Care about My Story?: Women and Gender Negotiation in the French and German Resistance during World War II., May 14, 2004 (Box 1)
  - Kramon, Eric, Giving South Africa "A More Human Face": The Black Consciousness Movement and Transformation in South Africa., May 14, 2004 (Box 2)
  - Kurren, Amy, "You've Got to be Carefully Taught": Interracial Relationships in Show Boat and South Pacific., May 2004 (Box 2)
  - Mittal, Sonia, The Olive Branch and the Sword: An Analytical Narrative of Moderate Involvement in the American Resistance Movement, 1774-1776., May 2004 (Box 2)
  - Roberts, Sophie, The Enemy Within: Zazous and Zoot Suiters, Swing, and Social Conflict in Wartime Paris and Los Angeles., May 14, 2004 (Box 2)
  - Schauf, Zach, Conformity to the Word: William Harrison and the Dilemmas of Reformation., May 14, 2004 (Box 2)
  - Song, Eugena, Competing Principles of Might and Right: Britain and the Middle Eastern Mandates 1919-1921., August 15, 2003 (Box 2)
  - Wechsler, Lauren, The Society for the Improvement of Elementary Teaching: Mutual Education and the Political Paradox of Restoration France., May 14, 2004 (Box 2)
  - Zakaras, Michael, Vintage Harvest: The Coming of Age of California Wine., May 21, 2004 (Box 2)
- Theses, 2004-2005; Accession ARCH-2005-195
  - Avina, Lauren Godinaz-, From la Hacienda to San Jose Viejo to San Jose Nuevo: The Formation of San Jose Piedras Blancas, Michoacan during Postrevolutionary Mexico., May 13, 2004 (Box 1)
  - Blair, Kathryn, An Obsession with Fusion: Edward Teller and the Moral Responsibility of Scientists., 2005 (Box 1)
  - Bomhack, Pat, Confronting the World: William Lloyd Garrison and the Ideal of Nonresistance, 1859-1862., May 20, 2005 (Box 1)
  - Brands, Hal, Contested Visions, Shifting Images: The United States and the Emperor of Japan, 1942-1946., May 1, 2005 (Box 1)
  - Coleman, Lindsay, Florentine Cassoni: Objects of Marriage, Culture and Display in Fifteenth-Century Florence., May 2005 (Box 1)
  - Crisham, Ellen Moore, Giving Children a Chance by Giving Parents a Choice: An historical look at parental participation and government involvement in the implementation of school voucher programs., May 17, 2005 (Box 1)
  - Ginsburg, Raphael J., Fashioning Authority: The Works of Leonhard Thurneisser zum Thurn., 2005 (Box 1)
  - Kim, Jennie, Wilsonianism: America Meets the World., May 2005 (Box 2)